能开始放电影了吗
Can we start the movie?
在谢尔顿到之前就开始吗
Before Sheldon gets here?
我们上次这样  他足足一个月不跟我们说话
Last time we did that, he didn't talk to us for a month.
还不快放
So do it!
等等嘛  他在哪呢
Hold on. Where is he?
根据他的短信  他刚才到二楼了
Well, according to his text, he was on the second floor,
但他得停下绑鞋带
then he stopped to tie his shoe.
绑好了  准备...
All tied, and...
-大家安安  -我们回来啦
- Hello! - ?Hi.
抱歉我们迟到了
Sorry we're late.
艾米绑我鞋带的速度慢死了
Amy took forever tying my shoe.
好的
All right!
是谁对看纪录片感到很兴奋啊
Who's excited to see a documentary?
这题我会
Oh, I know this one.
从来没人
Nobody ever.
别这样  这部绝对会很赞
Hey! This one's going to be great.
这部是在讲
This is about the rivalry
离经叛道酷炫科学家尼古拉·特斯拉
between a cool renegade scientist, Nikola Tesla,
与宿敌托马斯·爱迪生之间的仇恨
and his arch-nemesis, Thomas Edison.
这是科学界最赞的一段宿怨
It's the greatest scientific feud of all time.
都曾独立发明微积分  为谁先发明有过剧烈争执
莱布尼茨的微积分数学符号被更广泛地使用
莱布尼茨跟牛顿之间的血海深仇都可以忘了
I mean, you can forget about Leibniz and Newton.
已忘
Done.
特斯拉是发明电动汽车的人吗
So, Tesla's the one that invented the electric car?
佩妮  不是的
No, Penny.
那牌子的车只是以他的名字命名而已
No, the car is just named after him.
行行行  你也不需要拽成这样吧
Okay, you don't have to be so smug about it.
你去看恐怖片《小丑回魂》
You know, you went to see that movie It
英文片名为《It》与I.T.相近
还是因为你以为电影是讲恐怖程序员呢
because you thought it was about scary I.T. guys.
特斯拉是发明了我们的输电网络的天才
Tesla was a genius who invented our electrical grid.
而爱迪生只是想捞钱与博名气
Edison just wanted to get rich and famous.
他不是发明了灯泡吗
Didn't he invent the lightbulb?
他就想你这么以为
That's what he wants you to think.
但如果没有埃柏奈泽·肯纳斯理
But without the foundational work of Ebenezer Kinnersley,
沃伦·德拉鲁与詹姆士·鲍曼·琳赛打下的基础
Warren de la Rue and James Bowman Lindsay,
你对爱迪生的认识并不会多过你对
you wouldn't know Edison any more than you know
埃柏奈泽·肯纳斯理  沃伦·德拉鲁
Ebenezer Kinnersley, Warren de la Rue
或詹姆士·鲍曼·琳赛的认识
or James Bowman Lindsay.
他燃起来时是不是特性感
Isn't he sexy all fired up?
特斯拉是交流电之父
跟他之间的交流  电到了我
He really gets my current alternating,
懂我的哏吗
if you know what I mean.
爱迪生就是个沽名钓誉的恶霸
Edison was kind of a publicity hog and a bully.
爱迪生为了将特斯拉的交流电与恐怖做连结
用交流电电死了这只因伤人被判死刑的大象
他电死一只名为托普西的大象
Yeah, he electrocuted an elephant named Topsy
就为了让自己出名
just to make himself famous.
如果我有一只叫托普西的大象
If I had an elephant named Topsy,
我会让它生活优渥  衣食无忧
he would want for nothing.
还有  他的名字会叫小飞象
Also, he'd be named Jumbo.
更差的是  史上首个接吻影片是爱迪生录的
And worse than that, Edison filmed the first on-screen kiss,
他基本上就是个拍黄片的
so he's basically a pornographer.
不过每次我想把这话加进维基百科
Although every time I put that in Wikipedia,
都会被别人删掉
someone takes it out.
你现在还电气满满吗
Is your current still alternating?
幸好这里没有大象  否则...
We're lucky there aren't any elephants in here.
第十一季  第八集
昨晚那部纪录片
You know, that documentary last night was actually
-其实比我想象中要好看呢  -真的吗
- better than I thought it would be. - ?Really?
就那影片的结尾方式[电报]
Should've been about Samuel Morse
发明了电报用的摩尔斯电码
按理说应该讲萨缪尔·摩尔斯才对
the way they telegraphed that ending.
我已经为这笑话假笑过一次了
I already pretended to laugh at that joke once.
我们一定得再来一次吗
Do I have to do it again?
你能配合就再好不过了
Yeah, I'd appreciate it.
萨缪尔·摩尔斯  要被你笑死了
Samuel Morse. You kill me.
莱纳德  你能开车带我去上班吗
Leonard, can you drive me to work?
可以啊  对了  我们几个
Yeah, sure. Oh, hey, the guys and I
说到晚一点要去格里斐斯天文台
were talking about going to see the Tesla coil
看特斯拉线圈  要不要一起来
at the observatory later on, if you want to join.
抱歉去不了  我有事
Oh, I'm sorry, I can't. I'm busy.
-怎么了  你要干嘛  -莱纳德  你才要干嘛
- Why? What are you doing? - Leonard, what are you doing?
他说他去不了  摆出哭哭脸就完事了
He said he can't go. Make a sad face, move on.
没关系
It's fine.
我就是想告诉你也不行
I couldn't tell you even if I wanted to.
-这话什么意思  -莱纳德
- What does that mean? - ?Leonard!
哭哭脸  哭哭脸
Sad face, sad face.
我很乐意说  但我不行  你懂的
I mean, I would like to, but I just can't, you know,
因为这是最高机密
because it's classified and top secret.
等等  你还在为军方工作吗
Hold on, are you still working for the military?
你想出来真是太好了
I'm so glad you figured that out!
保密真是要把我给憋死了
It was killing me keeping it a secret!
他们不是炒了你们吗
I thought they fired you guys.
是啊  但是他们又重新雇了我
They did, but then they hired me back.
你最好不是在弄我们之前的项目
Well, you better not be working on our project,
因为我们可是团队
because we're a team.
莱纳德  "团队"两字里无"我"
Leonard, there is no "I" in team.
但是"我为军方干活
However, there is an "I" in
而你机会被我剥夺喔"这句里就有"我"
"I'm working with the military and you're not."
其实有五个发音带"呜哦"的字呢
There's five of them, in fact.
我有个大惊喜给你
I got a big surprise for you.
是派跟冰激凌吗
Is it pie and ice cream?
看来我是牛皮吹大了
Wow, did I oversell it.
是拉杰跟如琪
It's Raj and Ruchi!
-你好啊  -我们来啦
- Hello. - Hey. Hi.
你们两个怎么来啦
Hey, what are you two doing here?
不会打扰你太久
We won't stay long.
我就是来送给你
I just wanted to drop something off
我跟公司姑娘们送你的小礼物
from me and the girls at work.
公司的姑娘们没人喜欢我到愿意送我礼物
None of the girls at work like me enough to get me a gift.
那这样你就能理解为什么办公室里
Okay, so you'll know why everyone at the office
所有人都是同样的笔迹了
has the same handwriting.
很谢谢这份心意
I really appreciate the thought,
但不用这么客气  我很快能重回岗位
but it's not necessary. I'll be back soon.
不用担心工作  你需要休息多久就多久
Don't worry about work. You take all the time you need.
对啊  就关闭你的大脑
Yeah, just turn off your brain
让你的子宫施展它的魔法就行
and let your uterus do its magic.
它现在是这场表演的主角了
It's the star of the show now.
好了  本来不知道该让你们待多久
Okay, wasn't sure how long I should let you guys stay.
现在知道了  出去
Now I know! Get out!
很高兴看到你  你看起来气色很好
Good to see you. You look amazing.
谢谢你们来探望我
Thanks for coming!
这臭三八
That bitch.
别这样  拉杰也是一番好意
Oh, come on, he means well.
他也就是想让女朋友觉得他人好
He's just trying to impress his girlfriend.
我是在骂如琪
I'm talking about Ruchi.
她想抢我饭碗
She's after my job.
不然她干嘛说"你需要休息多久就多久"
Why do you think she said, "Take all the time you need"?
因为她人好啊
Because she was being nice?
才不是  她想趁我在家陪傻逼家人
No, she's trying to steal my projects while I'm at home
养这破盆栽时  抢走我的项目
taking care of this useless plant and my dumb family.
我说这话是因为我爱你
I'm only saying this because I love you
而且你从床上那里打不到我
and because you can't reach me from that bed,
但你听起来有点神经质
but you sound a little crazy.
我也爱你  但我也可以把这卡片当成
I love you, too, but I could fling this card in your eye
忍者手里剑来射爆你狗眼
like a ninja throwing star.
我才不信你
I don't believe you.
为什么军方会要谢尔顿啊
Why would the military want Sheldon?
我不知道啊  让他当靶子吗
I don't know. Target practice?
他最好不是在搞我们的导向系统
Well, he better not be working on our guidance system.
那可是我的点子
That was my idea.
我打给威廉姆斯上校
Why don't we call Colonel Williams
问问到底是什么情况吧
and find out what's going on.
很好  老子想要真相  他最好乖乖回答
Great. I want answers and he'd better give them to us.
两位好
Hello, gentlemen.
长官  莱纳德有问题问你
Hi, sir. Um, Leonard has a question.
谢尔顿是不是又在做我们之前的项目
Hey, is Sheldon working on our project again?
他这么说了吗
Did he say that?
没  他不愿意告诉我们
No, he wouldn't tell us.
原来他是能闭上嘴巴的
Huh. So he can keep his mouth shut.
那我该怎么做才能让他闭嘴呢
How do I get him to do that?
他到底有没有在做我们的导向系统项目
Is he working on our guidance system or not?
库珀博士联系了我们  说到了一个
Dr. Cooper contacted us with an idea on how to modify
修改你们的技术  来把它变成通信系统的点子
your technology into a communication system,
而这点子听起来不错
and it seemed interesting.
但这技术是我们团队开发出来的
But our team developed that technology.
而他是你们团队的领导
And he was your team leader.
谁说他是负责人了
Well, who said he was team leader?
他说的
He did.
我喜欢那种"掌控大局"的态度
And I like that kind of "take charge" attitude.
我们也可以有"掌控大局"的态度啊
We can have "take charge" attitudes.
那你俩怎么都没提出要当小组负责人呢
Then why didn't either of you ask to be team leader?
我们不想冒犯到其他人
We didn't want to step on anyone's toes.
对  我们在等你告诉我们
Yeah, so we were just waiting for you to
你认为谁...  好吧  我听出来了
tell us who you thought-- Okay, I hear it.
-说完了吗  -还没
- Are we done? - No, no.
我现在就要掌控大局  告诉你
I am taking charge right now and telling you
我们很不满意你...
that it is not okay with us if...
好吧  拜
Okay, bye.
我刚收到你的短信  没出什么事吧
Hey. I just got your text. Everything okay?
没事  只是有一件事想问你
Yeah, there's just something I need to ask you.
妮妮  我会高兴死的
Oh, Bernie, I'd be thrilled.
不是要叫你当我的生育指导
It's not be my birth coach.
伤心了  但幸好我懂如何调整呼吸撑过去
Okay, that hurts, but luckily I know how to breathe through it.
我要你查出  如琪是否想趁我卧床休养时
I need you to find out if Ruchi's trying to steal
抢走我的研究项目
my projects at work while I'm on bed rest.
她不是那种人
She's not that kind of a person.
她慷慨大方  乐善好施
She's-she's generous and charitable.
你这么说纯粹是因为她愿意跟你睡
You're just saying that 'cause she's sleeping with you.
对啊  这是我最喜欢的善举
Yes, that's my favorite charity.
我知道感觉很多疑  但我真的感到很脆弱
I know I sound paranoid, but I'm feeling really vulnerable.
要是你能查出点消息  那就太好了
If there's anything you could find out, it'd be great.
如果她真的有企图  你打算怎么做
And if she is up to anything, what are you gonna do?
什么都不做
Nothing.
我只会平静地跟她解释
I'll just calmly talk to her and explain
做人要懂得尊重界线
there are certain boundaries that need to be respected.
这都是为了公司里的大家好
It's really for the benefit of everyone at the company.
你的语气听起来很平和
Uh, okay, what you're saying sounds nice,
但你说话的语气
but the way you're saying it
让我的蛋蛋都吓得缩进小腹了
is causing my testicles to take cover in my abdomen.
你想看什么
What do you want to watch?
你来选吧
Oh, why don't you pick.
好啊  喜剧怎么样
Okay, how about comedy?
我今天已经笑过了
Eh, I already laughed today.
我知道  在我踢到脚趾头的时候
I know. It was when I stubbed my toe.
还是很好笑
Still funny.
剧情片呢
Drama?
不了  我今天已经看过别人哭了
Nah, I've already seen someone cry today.
当时真的很疼  谢尔顿
It really hurt, Sheldon!
我们和威廉姆斯上校谈过了
We talked to Colonel Williams.
他全都告诉我们了
He told us everything.
不好意思  能不能改天再说这个
I'm sorry, can we do this another time?
艾米快要意识到她想看浩克系列电影啦
Amy's just about to realize she wants to watch a Hulk marathon.
出什么事了
What's going on?
谢尔顿背着我们偷偷去找空军
Sheldon went to the Air Force behind our backs.
我才没做这种事
I did nothing of the sort.
我有个想法
I had an idea
一种基于微中子的通讯系统
for a neutrino-based communication system,
我告诉了他们  他们很感兴趣
I presented it to them, and they were interested.
但你的通讯系统
But y-your communication system
是根据我们的导向系统制造的
was based on our guidance system.
声呐也是根据蝙蝠制造的
And sonar is based on bats.
你也没见它们倒挂在
You don't see them hanging upside down
专利律师的办公室里啊
in a patent attorney's office.
你知道吗  你喜欢把自己比作特斯拉
You know what, you like to think that you're just like Tesla,
但事实就是  你跟爱迪生一模一样
but the truth is you're exactly like Edison.
收回这句话
You take that back.
不  他说得对
No, he's right.
你就是个爱抢功劳  自我吹捧的恶霸
You are a bully, a credit hog and a self-promoter.
要说这里真有谁像特斯拉  那也是我们
And if anyone around here is like Tesla, it's us.
就是啊
Yeah.
你敢相信他们说我跟爱迪生一模一样吗
Can you believe they said I was just like Edison?
而且还当着一位淑女的面
Yeah, and in front of a lady, no less.
你确实是在他们的研究基础上继续发展
Well, you are building on their work
还把功劳揽上身
and taking the credit for it.
这是典型爱迪生会干的事
That's a classic Edison move.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
如果我是爱迪生  而你爱我
Well, if I'm Edison and you love me,
那这说明你又是什么人呢
then what does that say about you?
老实说  我真的不知道
I honestly don't know.
好吧
Okay.
我得上网去查查爱迪生太太了
Well, I have to Google some stuff about Mrs. Edison.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
你知道这是谁的错吗
You know whose fault this is?
我知道
I do.
你的错
Yours.
不  是我妈的
No, my mother's.
"去交朋友吧  谢尔顿"
"Go make friends, Sheldon."
结果呢
What happens?
20年后  他们给我起绰号骂我
20 years later, they call me names.
我觉得他们叫你什么不是重点
I don't think what they called you is the point here.
是吗  那要是我用你不喜欢的
Oh, yeah? How would you feel
神经系统科学家的名字来叫你  你会作何感想
if I called you the name of a neuroscientist you didn't like?
你知道任何神经系统科学家的名字吗
Do you know the name of any neuroscientist?
当然了
Of course.
除了我之外
Not me?
那就没了
Then no.
你觉得他们是对的吗  艾米
Do you think they're right, Amy?
你觉得我像爱迪生一样吗
Do you think I'm like Edison?
谢尔顿  我觉得你不开心
Sheldon, I don't think you're upset
不是因为他们说你像哪种科学家
because of what kind of scientist they said you're like.
而是因为
I think you're upset because
你的朋友们内心受伤了
your friend's feelings got hurt.
你说得对
You're right.
我太在乎别人的感受了
I care too much about other people's feelings.
这向来是我的致命弱点
It's always been my fatal flaw.
谢尔顿  我觉得不...
Sheldon, I don't think...
先别说话  艾米  我正在成长呢
No, no, not now, Amy. I'm growing as a person.
刚才真爽
Ah, that was fun.
伸出你的小拳拳
Put her there, buddy.
我才不要跟你睡完后击拳庆祝呢
I am not fist bumping you after we have sex.
是你说想保持玩玩的关系
You're the one who wanted to keep things casual.
玩玩和怪异是有区别的
There's a difference between casual and weird.
对我来说没有
Not the way I do it.
你今天过得怎么样
So, um... how was, how was your day?
工作顺利吗
Like, how's-how's work?
很好
Oh, great.
伯纳黛特走了之后
With Bernadette gone,
她的项目都由我负责了
I'm getting to handle all her projects.
她不是走了
Well, she's-she's not gone.
她很快会回来
She'll be back soon.
但愿不会太快
Not too soon, let's hope.
原来如琪真的想
So it turns out Ruchi is totally
抢走伯纳黛特的项目
trying to take over Bernadette's projects.
她就突然告诉你了吗
Wow, she just told you that out of the blue?
是啊  我们当时刚做完爱
Yeah, yeah, we had just made love.
画面太美
It was so beautiful.
我俩焦糖色的胴体
Our caramel-colored bodies
像色情的太妃糖般交缠在一起
were entwined like erotic taffy...
说重点
Get to the point!
抱歉
Uh, sorry, uh, yeah.
我问起她的工作  她就承认了
I-I asked her about work, and she just admitted
她在觊觎伯纳黛特的项目
she has her eyes on Bernadette's projects.
真不敢相信她会这样
Can't believe she would take advantage
占一个孕妇的便宜
of a pregnant lady like that.
那你做了什么
So what did you do?
你说呢
What do you think I did?
我跟她闲聊了20分钟后又再打了一炮
I made small talk for 20 minutes and had sex again.
你一定要告诉妮妮
You have to say something to Bernie.
我不确定  要是我告诉她  她一定会质问如琪
I don't know. If I do that, she's gonna confront Ruchi,
如琪就不会再跟我打炮了
and then Ruchi's gonna stop sleeping with me.
拉杰  你不能继续睡一个
Raj, you can't go on sleeping with a woman
想搞死你朋友的女人
who's trying to screw over your friend.
不能睡还是必须睡
Can't or must?
那个导向系统是我的点子
You know, that guidance system was my idea.
是你想通了该如何实现
You figured out how to make it work.
我们根本就不需要谢尔顿
We didn't even need Sheldon.
别忘了你的点子是建立在我的理论上的
Let's not forget your idea was based on my theory.
我们正在骂谢尔顿呢  别内讧
Hey, we're bagging on Sheldon here! Focus!
他能想到用我们的量子技术
I guess it was pretty smart using our quantum technology
作为通信系统的基础  还是挺聪明的
as the basis for a communication system.
如果他把氦替换为氙  效果会更好
Be even better if he swapped out the helium for xenon.
那样就不需要将温度保持在零下271度
Ooh. So instead of having to keep it at negative 271 degrees,
而是零下108度就行了
you'd only have to keep it at negative 108.
这样就更高效了
It would be way more efficient.
氙有更大的核
And xenon has a bigger nucleus,
其相干性会让它的成为更易发现的信号
so coherence would make it an easier signal to see.
你真是天才
You're brilliant!
我们应该告诉谢尔顿
We should tell Sheldon.
你真是蠢材
You're an idiot!
我们才不要告诉谢尔顿
We don't tell Sheldon.
我们背着他偷偷联系军队
We go to the military behind his back
就像他背叛我们一样背叛他
and we screw him like he screwed us.
你是对的  你是对的  我们不需要他
All right, you're right, you're right, we don't need him.
我们可以自己来
We can do this all on our own.
-其中的运算你能行吗  -不行
- Do you think you can do the math? - No.
但如果其他人算出来了
But if someone else does it,
我绝对能狠狠验算一遍
I can double check the crap out of it.
我想告诉你  我按你的吩咐去做了
I want you to know, I did what you asked.
我和如琪聊了工作上的事
I talked to Ruchi and found out what's going on at work.
所以她是试图想偷走我的项目吗
So is she trying to steal my projects?
不  不是试图  是差不多已经得到了
No, not trying to, sounds like it's a done deal.
来  吃块巧克力蛋糕吧
Here, have a brownie.
我要杀了她
I'm gonna kill her.
好啦  不要记恨如琪
Okay, don't take this out on Ruchi.
她是想偷走你的工作吗  是的
Is she trying to take your job? Yes.
她的车是停在你的车位吗  是的
Is she parking in your space? Yes.
她在昨天的会议上取笑
Did she get a laugh at a meeting yesterday
你是"博纳带球"  好笑吗  笑成一片
by calling you "Pregnadette"? Big one.
但你也会和她做同样的事  你自己清楚
But you would've done the exact same thing, and you know it.
我才不会在同事背后捅刀呢
I never would've undermined a coworker.
什么  少来  还记得那个艾瑞克吗
What? Oh, please. Wh-What about that guy Eric,
你明明知道老板有哮喘
who you told it was "Bring Your Cat to Work Day"
还故意骗他说有"带猫上班日"
when you knew your boss had asthma?
我只是想捉弄他
That was just a hilarious prank
谁知道我因此得到了大间的办公室呢
that ended with me getting a corner office.
我想说的是在你攻击如琪之前
All I'm saying is before you attack Ruchi,
也许你应该在镜子里好好看看自己
maybe you should take a long hard look in the mirror,
因为你会看到
because you know what you'll see--
除了你闪亮的皮肤和奢华浓密的金发之外
apart from radiant skin and luxuriously thick hair?
有一个虚伪小人
Hypocrisy!
确实浓密
It is thick.
你觉得如何  你能算出来吗
So what do you think? Can you make it work?
我只需要用横截面
Uh, I just need to use the cross section
算出相互作用的概率
to calculate the probability of the interaction.
我们能帮忙吗
Can we help?
可以
Yes.
帮忙我去买一罐品客薯片吧
Why don't you run get me a can of Pringles.
莱纳德  我...
Leonard, I was--
克里普奇在这里干什么
What's Kripke doing here?
他正在帮我们开发一种更好  更高效的
Oh, he's just helping us develop a better, more efficient
中微子通讯系统  我们就能联系军队
neutrino comm system that we're gonna pitch to the military,
彻底打垮你
making yours obsolete.
没错  是莱纳德想出来的
Yeah, Leonard thought of it.
-非常聪明  -谢谢
- It's genius. - ?Oh, thanks.
我没有用液氦而是用...
You see, instead of using liquid helium...
-妈呀  快闭嘴  -对不起
- Good God, man, shut up! - Right, sorry.
你没说算这个是为了整治谢尔顿呀
You didn't tell me we were doing this just to stick it to Sheldon.
那个...
Oh, well...
逗你玩呢  这不是锦上添花吗
I messing with you. This sundae just got a cherry on top!
好吧  祝你们好运
Fine. Good luck to you.
军方已经对我的系统感兴趣了
The military is already interested in my system,
我的运算也都完成了
and my math is worked out.
他的运算中还有一个大空白
His still has a big gap in it.
在哪里
Where?
就这儿
There.
我可以问一个问题吗
Can I ask you a question? ?
如果一种药的头号副作用是让人不停地哭
Does a drug still count as an antidepressant
它还能算是抗抑郁剂吗
if its number one side effect is uncontrollable weeping?
不知道  反正我每次哭完都觉得好爽
I don't know. I always feel better after a good cry.
我一直想问问博纳黛特的意见
I've been trying to ask Bernadette,
但她完全不回我的短信
but she's not answering any of my texts.
听着  我觉得她有点被你威胁到了
Yeah, uh, listen, I think she might be a little threatened by you, you know,
因为你能系自己的鞋带  大笑时不会漏尿
because you can tie your own shoes and laugh without peeing.
她对你说什么了吗
Did she say something to you?
没有
No.
好吧  说了一点
I mean, well, kind of.
不过没事的  她是荷尔蒙作祟
But it's okay. She's just hormonal.
你也别担心  我为你说话了
And, you know, don't worry, I stood up for you.
我才不需要你为我说话呢
I don't need you to stand up for me.
你又不是我男朋友
You're not my boyfriend.
我很关心你
Look, I care about you,
你可以说这一切不代表什么
and you can say that this doesn't mean anything,
但事实上我俩算是在交往中
but the truth is we're in a relationship, okay?
总有一天你得想出办法面对这事
And you're gonna have to figure out some way to deal with it.
真不敢相信她居然把我甩了
I can't believe she dumped me.
好难回答  因为我完全能相信啊
This is tough for me, 'cause I can.
很遗憾事情最后变成这样
Sorry things worked out like that.
因为我痛苦分手  还是因为你失去了一个间谍
Because I'm in pain or because you don't have a spy anymore?
你知道我很遗憾就够了
Let's just leave it at "I'm sorry."
你已经够伤心了
You're already sad.
根据克里普奇的计算
Based on Kripke's calculations,
我们应该能成功
I think this is gonna work.
也许我们应该今天去跟威廉上校说说
Maybe we should pitch it to Colonel Williams today.
干嘛把自己局限于美国军队呢
Why limit ourselves to the U.S. Military?
肯定还有很多人想要我们的项目呢
I bet there's a lot of other places we could take this.
我是说不会被当成间谍抓起来的那种
Without committing criminal espionage?
打击别人的想法不要钱是吧  莱纳德
You know, it's easy to shoot an idea down, Leonard.
我想我应该恭喜两位了
Well, I suppose congratulations are in order.
你们想打击我  你们成功了
You set out to destroy me, and you achieved your goal.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
军队取消了我的项目
The military canceled my project,
因为他们要和你们合作了
because they're going with yours.
不可能  我们根本还没联系呢
That's impossible. We haven't even pitched it yet.
威廉上校告诉我加州理工的另一个团队
Well, Colonel Williams said another team at Caltech
开发出了更高效的中微子通讯系统
came up with a more efficient neutrino comm system.
我去
Damn it!
我们离开一下
Excuse us.
克里普奇
Kripke.
怎么了  各位
What's up, fellas?
你背叛了我们吗
Did you screw us over?
哇  我可不能告诉你
Ooh, I can't tell you that.
这是机密
It's classified.
你们干嘛把点子告诉巴里·克里普奇
Why did you tell Barry Kripke your idea?
这都怪你俩
This is all your fault.
不  是你的错
No, it's your fault.
如果你一开始就和我们联手
If you would've come to us in the beginning,
这些烂事就不会发生了
none of this would've happened.
如果能安慰到你们的话  你们都做错了
Well, if it helps, you all behaved terribly
你们自食恶果完全活该
and you deserve what you got.
完全没有好吗
Well, that doesn't help at all.
有时候你的社交技巧真是令人发指
You know, sometimes your social skills are very poor.
真不敢相信我们被克里普奇利用了
Can't believe we let Kripke use us like that.
也许你们都更像那个
You know, maybe you're all more like the guy
电动汽车以他为名却不是他发明的家伙
who didn't invent the electric car
而不像那个其实没发明灯泡的家伙吧
and less like the guy who didn't invent the lightbulb.
她说得对  也许我们全都是特斯拉
She's right. Maybe we're all a bunch of Teslas after all.
特斯拉最后不是默默无闻地死于贫穷和癫狂吗
Didn't Tesla die penniless, forgotten and insane?
你对她社交技巧的评价太到位了
You may have a point about her social skills.
他才没有发疯
He wasn't insane.
他的确有爱上了一只鸽子
He did fall in love with a pigeon.
如果特斯拉喜欢小小丑丑的东西
Well, if we're gonna call Tesla crazy
就要被说成是疯子的话
for loving something small and unappealing,
不如马上把佩妮关进疯人院吧
might as well put Penny in a padded cell right now.